

## Profile

Good in teams and overall calm person. Like to interact with other people. Software Engineer specialized in Javascript. Both front-end oriented and back-end oriented, with NodeJS. Keeping complex programs simple.

Test Engineer specialized in test automation setup. From checks in the code editor and pull request until tool selection, setup and implementation for unit and integration tests.

Team Builder, Goal Oriented, Problem Solver and Quality Focused.

# Freelance History

## **Company Spero Solutions, Utrecht**

December 2018 — Present

Founded for providing IT services.

#### Frontend Engineer at ING, Amsterdam

March 2021 — Present

Hired to rebuild the 'move-money' component for the ING website.

Next to working on this redesign / rebuild, I worked on maintenance and new features of other related components.

Worked with WebComponents, JS, lit-html, Azure DevOp among others.

#### Sabbatical, Europe

November 2021 — March 2022

Visiting the Canary Islands with my girlfriend in a camper van.

## Frontend Developer at Cloom, Amsterdam

March 2021 — November 2021

Hired to build a live video web application for a newly founded startup.

Worked mainly on building the frontend application in VueJS. Next to that I performed some backend work in NodeJS and shaped a part of the environment in AWS.

Worked with multiple AWS services, NodeJS, VueJS, Twilio Video (live), SendGrid, GitHub Actions, Cognito among others.

#### Software QA Engineer at ING, Amsterdam

November 2019 — March 2021

Hired to raise the quality of the investment software for ING.

Worked mainly on performance testing and creating tooling for the teams to do analysis regarding the quality of ING's backend system.

Worked with Jenkins CI/CD, Docker, OpenShift, Vagrant, Groovy, Java, Oracle, JS, JMeter, Grafana, InfluxDB, SoapUI among others.

#### Sabbatical, Europe

May 2019 — October 2019

Travelling through Europe with my girlfriend in a camper van.

#### **Details**

Hoorn NH, Netherlands

Date / Place of birth

18 - 03 - 1990

Woerden

Nationality

Dutch

Driving license

В

#### **Skills**

JS

NodeJS

PolymerJS / lit-html

JS Frameworks (like: VueJS React, Ember.JS, Angular, Polymer, LitElements, NodeJS, self-made frameworks among others)

WebComponents

Kubernetes / Openshift

HTML & CSS

AWS Services (Cognito, Lambda, Beanstalk among others)

Azure DevOps

Webpack

Java

Docker

**PWA** 

Git

Travis CI

Wide variety of mobile and web testing tooling / frameworks / techniques

## Languages

Dutch - native

English - professional

German - novice

French - novice

## Quality Engineer at Topicus Europort+, Gouda

January 2019 — May 2019

Hired to raise the quality of an investment software solution for big banks in the Netherlands and Belgium. Organized training for developers and sprint meetings for all testers.

Worked with Jenkins CI/CD, SoapUI, Docker, Vagrant, Groovy, Oracle, JS among others.

# Employment History

#### Web Developer at IceMobile, Amsterdam

April 2016 — January 2019

Built end consumer websites and client facing websites. CI/CD for web projects. Set web standards for all web projects in 2018, now using the latest and greatest.

Worked on NodeJS services. Amazon and Openshift environments.

Worked with VanillaJS, React, NodeJS, HTML, CSS, PWA, Leanplum, Jenkins, Openshift among many others.

## Software Engineer at IceMobile, Amsterdam

December 2014 — September 2015

Test automation setup for Android, iOS and Web on real devices.

CI/CD for mobile. NodeJS backend. Bluetooth beacons.

#### Air Traffic Controller in training at Skeyes, Steenokkerzeel

September 2015 — March 2016

# Air Traffic Controller in training at Luchtverkeersleiding Nederland, Schiphol-Oost

August 2009 — March 2010

#### All-round Flexer at Ipse de Bruggen, Zwammerdam, Netherlands

May 2007 — September 2009

Employee at an institution for mentally challenged/impaired people.

Domestic environment, daytime activities, night shifts, mix of different groups.

#### Education

#### Informatica, Haagse Hogeschool, Den Haag, Zoetermeer

February 2011 — November 2014

## Air Traffic Controller, Skeyes, Steenokkerzeel

September 2015 — March 2016

Training not completed.

## Air Traffic Controller, Luchtverkeersleiding Nederland, Schiphol-Oost

August 2009 — March 2010

Basic Theory module, Aerodrome Control Instrument module achieved.

Training not completed.

#### HAVO - Nature Science and Economics, Minkema College, Woerden

September 2002 — June 2007

#### **Hobbies**

Field hockey, Touring with our firetruck camper van, Concerts and festivals, Card games, Hang out with friends, Traveling Interested in Tech and Science

# Internships

#### Software Developer at IceMobile, Amsterdam

May 2014 — September 2014

Built test automation platform for mobile apps in a continuous integration environment for iOS and Android.

## Software Developer at IceMobile, Amsterdam

September 2013 — January 2014

Built holiday hour system.

## Y Extra-curricular activities

## Code Dojo Volunteer (Voluntary) at the library, Hoorn

October 2020 — Present

Supporting children from 8-17 who like programming. Things we use are WoofJS, Microbits and Scratch.

## Remote Teacher (Voluntary) at Digitale Topschool, Amsterdam

July 2012 — August 2018

Supporting intelligent children from 10-12 with challenging assignments via an online platform.

## Sponsor Committee Member (Voluntary) at MHC Woerden, Woerden

September 2011 — August 2013

Part of a group whom created a new club image, introduced a loyalty program at the club, set up and maintained a narrowcasting system, setup and/or maintained several websites.